<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:etd="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd" version="3.5">
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Toward Critical Consciousness: 
The Dynamic Consciousness of Adolescent Refugee English Learners</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:name type="personal">
    <mods:namePart type="given">Robin</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Schell</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/aut">Author</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-16T10:15:42-04:00</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="edtf">2019-08</mods:dateIssued>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:recordInfo displayLabel="Submission">
    <mods:recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-16T10:15:42-04:00</mods:recordCreationDate>
    <mods:recordChangeDate keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019-07-16T10:15:42-04:00</mods:recordChangeDate>
  </mods:recordInfo>
  <mods:extension>
    <etd:degree>
      <etd:level>Doctoral (includes post-doctoral)</etd:level>
      <etd:name>Doctor of Philosophy</etd:name>
      <etd:discipline>Education</etd:discipline>
      <etd:grantor>University of Tennessee</etd:grantor>
    </etd:degree>
  </mods:extension>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Clara Lee</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Brown</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/ths">Thesis advisor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Clara Lee</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Brown</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">Committee member</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Chonika</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Coleman-King</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">Committee member</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Susan</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Groenke</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">Committee member</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Dolly</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Young</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">Committee member</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:typeOfResource>text</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2014026039">Academic theses</mods:genre>
  <mods:genre authority="coar" valueURI="http://purl.org/coar/resource_type/c_db06">doctoral thesis</mods:genre>
  <mods:language>
    <mods:languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</mods:languageTerm>
  </mods:language>
  <mods:abstract>Thousands of migrant and refugee children with limited or interrupted formal education enroll in U.S. schools each year. Mainstream society positions them at the margins of society, by default, placing them at risk of adopting impoverished identities that preclude full participation in society. Development of critical consciousness has been explored as a way to empower youth to become agentive in authoring their own lives. This study describes the nature of critical consciousness, or the recognition and challenge of oppression through agentive acts, expressed by adolescent refugee English learners (ELs). The ELs’ perceptions of injustices in their lives formed the basis of collective interrogation and challenge of injustice in two urban middle school English as a Second Language (ESL) classrooms. Culture circles, modeled on Freire (1970/ 1996) and Souto-Manning (2010) and thematic literacy units were the means to implement critical pedagogy intended to draw out students’ critical consciousness expressions. Audio-recordings of culture circles, other class sessions, and semi-structured interviews, along with student writing were collected, transcribed. Thematic analysis was conducted using a template approach based on Freire’s (1970/1996) critical consciousness continuum using the categories semi-intransitive consciousness, naïve consciousness, and critical consciousness. The template went through several iterations as analysis revealed Freire’s categories to be insufficient in describing forms of agency and action evident in the data. The final analysis revealed dynamic and transcategorical tendencies in the ELs’ consciousness. Varying degrees of critical awareness, agency, and action were manifested simultaneously, making it difficult to accurately analyze using template based on Freire. However, it was clear that the students’ levels of agency did not align with their levels of critical awareness. Thus, this study highlights the urgency of practicing critical pedagogy in ESL classrooms to nurture students’ sense of agency, a necessary precursor of action. Teachers must afford students opportunities to grapple with injustice in a supportive environment in which they can safely voice their opinions and concerns and be encouraged to act or advocate on their own behalf. In so doing, teachers may nurture students’ critical consciousness development and thereby help them to succeed in school and become full participants in society.</mods:abstract>
  <mods:note displayLabel="Submitted Comment"/>
  <mods:relatedItem type="series">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Graduate Theses and Dissertations</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:note displayLabel="Keywords Submitted by Author">English Language Learners, English Learners, ELL, ELs, English as a Second Lanugage, ESL, Teaching English to Speakers of other Languages, TESOL, critical consciousness, critical pedagogy, refugee, adolescent, middle school, urban education, agency, social justice</mods:note>
  <mods:accessCondition type="local rights statement"> Unless otherwise noted, (c) 2017 The Author(s).</mods:accessCondition>
<mods:note displayLabel="Copyright holder">author</mods:note><mods:physicalDescription><mods:note displayLabel="Publication Status">PUBLISHED</mods:note></mods:physicalDescription></mods:mods>
