<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:etd="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd" version="3.5">
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Role of Polymer and Nanoparticle Properties on the Dynamics and Local Structure of Polymer Nanocomposites</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:name type="personal">
    <mods:namePart type="given">Robert</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Carroll</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/aut">Author</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf">2019-06-19T17:17:35-04:00</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="edtf">2019-08</mods:dateIssued>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:recordInfo displayLabel="Submission">
    <mods:recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2019-06-19T17:17:35-04:00</mods:recordCreationDate>
    <mods:recordChangeDate keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019-06-19T17:17:35-04:00</mods:recordChangeDate>
  </mods:recordInfo>
  <mods:extension>
    <etd:degree>
      <etd:level>Doctoral (includes post-doctoral)</etd:level>
      <etd:name>Doctor of Philosophy</etd:name>
      <etd:discipline>Physics</etd:discipline>
      <etd:grantor>University of Tennessee</etd:grantor>
    </etd:degree>
  </mods:extension>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Alexei</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Sokolov</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/ths">Thesis advisor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Mark</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Dadmun</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">Committee member</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Steve</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Johnston</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">Committee member</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart type="given">Adriana</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="family">Moreo</mods:namePart>
    <mods:namePart type="termsOfAddress"/>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">Committee member</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:typeOfResource>text</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:genre authority="lcgft" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/genreForms/gf2014026039">Academic theses</mods:genre>
  <mods:genre authority="coar" valueURI="http://purl.org/coar/resource_type/c_db06">doctoral thesis</mods:genre>
  <mods:language>
    <mods:languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</mods:languageTerm>
  </mods:language>
  <mods:abstract>Polymer nanocomposite (PNC) research is a burgeoning field of study in material science &#13;
owing to the interesting material properties afforded to nanoscale interaction between polymer &#13;
and nanoparticle. Despite the wealth of different applications being pursued for study, the &#13;
fundamental parameters that control these emergent properties are not well understood. These &#13;
knowledge gaps include what controls the interfacial polymer layer 1-5nm away from the &#13;
nanoparticle surface as well as what role nanoparticle characteristics play in affecting the &#13;
macroscopic properties of PNCs. This dissertation combines different static and dynamic &#13;
experimental techniques to probe both polymer- and nanoparticle-specific parameters with the &#13;
goal of understanding how they control dynamics and local structure in PNCs. For the polymer &#13;
perspective, it is first demonstrated that a heterogeneous model analysis of the dielectric spectra &#13;
of PNCs is the most accurate method to describe PNC spectra; this analysis reveals that the &#13;
interfacial polymer layer grows significantly with cooling and that the chains in the interface &#13;
have less freedom of motion because of chain stretching. This analysis is further used to &#13;
demonstrate that polymer chain rigidity increases the extent of the interfacial layer above a &#13;
critical rigidity. The conformational state of polymers is further explored with dielectric &#13;
spectroscopy where stretched or flattened chains are shown to have a reduced dielectric &#13;
amplitude from the neat polymer. From the nanoparticle perspective, unique macroscopic &#13;
properties are shown to be achievable with small, attractive 2nm nanoparticles (NPs) that are on &#13;
the order of a polymer segment size. These PNCs with 2nm NPs differ from PNCs with &#13;
conventionally sized NPs studied previously by having large changes in mechanical properties &#13;
while simultaneously having small changes in viscoelastic properties at high temperatures. These&#13;
effects are attributed to enhanced NP mobility, which is controlled by the temperature-sensitive &#13;
polymer-NP desorption time. The diffusion of nanoparticles in a polymer melt is studied to better &#13;
understand how polymer-NP desorption time controls the NP motion. The diffusion results are &#13;
explained with a simple model which argues that NPs transition from a NP-dominant core-shell &#13;
mechanism to a polymer-dominant vehicle mechanism as the MW of the polymer increases, a &#13;
transition which depends on NP size and the polymer-NP desorption time.</mods:abstract>
  <mods:note displayLabel="Submitted Comment"/>
  <mods:relatedItem type="series">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Graduate Theses and Dissertations</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:note displayLabel="Keywords Submitted by Author">polymer nanocomposite, polymer dynamics, nanoparticle diffusion, interfacial layer, dielectric spectroscopy, desorption time</mods:note>
  <mods:accessCondition type="local rights statement"> Unless otherwise noted, (c) 2017 The Author(s).</mods:accessCondition>
<mods:note displayLabel="Copyright holder">author</mods:note><mods:physicalDescription><mods:note displayLabel="Publication Status">PUBLISHED</mods:note></mods:physicalDescription></mods:mods>
